{
    "id": "54462fe647ab4c36b8b21a0f57654aa6",
    "title": "Comparative and superlative exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "f15f075f3be04bec85ea87c531113400",
            "title": "Comparative and superlative quiz",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He was older .................... I thought.",
                    "description": "'Than' is the word used in comparative structures. 'Then' is an adverb indicating time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "then",
                        "than",
                        "as",
                        "like"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "China is ............................ India.",
                    "description": "Adjectives of one or two syllables form their comparative forms by adding -er to the positive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "bigger then",
                        "bigger than",
                        "more big than"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Susie is .................................... of the four girls.",
                    "description": "We use the comparative to compare one person or thing with another person or thing. We use the superlative to compare somebody or something with the whole group they/it belong(s) to. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "the prettier",
                        "prettier",
                        "the prettiest",
                        "prettiest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am not as ................................... my brother.",
                    "description": "We use the structure as...as... to make comparisons using positive adjectives.",
                    "answers": [
                        "successful as",
                        "successful so",
                        "successful than",
                        "more successful than"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "That was the ................................ thing to do.",
                    "description": "The article 'the' indicates that a superlative adjective is following.",
                    "answers": [
                        "stupid",
                        "funnier",
                        "funny",
                        "funniest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was ...................................... gift I have ever received.",
                    "description": "The comparative is used in expressions with than.",
                    "answers": [
                        "most expensive",
                        "the most expensive",
                        "the more expensive"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "For .................................. information, please visit our website.",
                    "description": "Farther indicates distance. Further means additional.",
                    "answers": [
                        "further",
                        "farther",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She owns a ............................. collection of antiques.",
                    "description": "The article 'a' indicates that we need a positive adjective here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "fine",
                        "finer",
                        "finest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was ............................... than I was expecting.",
                    "description": "The conjunction 'than' indicates that we need a comparative adjective here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "cheap",
                        "cheaper",
                        "cheapest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They are both good girls, but I think Mary is the .................. of the two.",
                    "description": "We do not normally use the superlative when the group includes only two persons or things.",
                    "answers": [
                        "good",
                        "better",
                        "best",
                        "gooder"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the ................................ kitchen I have ever seen.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "filthy",
                        "filthier",
                        "most filthy",
                        "filthiest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "The older I get, .......................................",
                    "description": "The word order in both clauses should be: the + comparative expression + subject + verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "the happy I am",
                        "I am the happier",
                        "the happier I am",
                        "I am happier"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}